《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
杀了法尔科内只会制造混乱
Killing Falcone would only create chaos.
我需要吸取他的力量
I need to siphon his strength.
等时机一到
So when the time is right,
推翻他的统治
taking over his organization
就会如同戴手套一样轻松
will be like slipping on a glove.
我总是好生气
I'm so angry all the time.
这感觉会消退吗
Will that ever go away?
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred...
你能教我打斗吗
...can you teach me how to fight?
我知道你受了折磨
Look, you've been through a lot.
我很害怕  吉姆
I am scared, Jim.
不管我去哪里
Everywhere I go
我都能感觉到那怪物萨斯
I can feel that monster, Zsasz.
戈登
Gordon.
有巡警抓回来个罪犯
Some unis brought in a perp.
自称认识你
Claims to know you.
你好啊  警探
Hey, Detective.
想我了吗
Miss me?
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
芭芭拉
Barbara?
挺不错啊
Sweet crib.
你还真是个有钱的警察
You must be one rich cop.
这是我女朋友的家
It's my girlfriend's place.
她人呢
Where is she?
不知道  芭芭拉
I don't know. Barbara?
接下来怎样
So... what?
我一个人留在这里吗
I get to stay here alone?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
亲爱的吉姆
Dear Jim,
我以为我能为你勇敢坚强起来  可我做不到
I thought I could be strong and brave for you, but I can't.
无论我去哪里  眼前都会出现法尔科内和萨斯
Every place I go, I see Falcone and Zsasz.
我紧张不安  渴求安慰  一片混乱
I'm nervous and needy and screwed up,
你一定不想要也不需要这样的我
and I know that's not what you need or want,
我会暂时离开  努力振作起来
so I'm going away for a while, to get myself together.
我是戈登
This is Gordon.
是的
Uh... uh, right.
我们在顶楼  上来吧
We're in the penthouse. Come on up.
看来你女朋友是不会回来了  是吧
Sounds like your girlfriend's not coming back, huh?
她为什么害怕法尔科内
Why's she worried about Falcone?
不关你的事
None of your business.
现在怎么办
So what happens now?
你要撤销对我的起诉吗
You gonna get the charges against me dropped?
我会的  但你是我韦恩案的唯一目击证人
I will, but you're my only witness to the Wayne murders.
你要再把我拷在排水管上吗
You gonna cuff me to a drainpipe again?
不  我不会强制关押你
No, I'm not gonna hold you against your will.
哥谭市警局  少管所  你都能轻易逃脱
GCPD, juvie-- you'd just break out.
这么说我能待在这里了
So I do get to stay here.
不行  我找了别的地方
No, I have someplace else in mind.
人像速写师来了
That's the sketch artist.
我要你跟他描述枪击韦恩夫妇的人的外貌特征
I need you to describe the man who shot the Waynes.
等等  我要去哪里
Wait, where am I going to stay?
韦恩庄园
Wayne Manor.
黑门监狱
不要和犯人讲话
Do not speak to the inmate.
不要在职责范围之外碰触犯人
Do not touch the inmate unless in the service of your job.
任何情况下不要接受犯人给的东西
Do not accept anything from the inmate under any circumstances.
这人是谁
Who is this guy, anyway?
伊恩・哈格罗夫  一个"高明"的爆破犯
Name's Ian Hargrove, some genius bomb maker.
在哥谭及周边地区炸了十余幢大楼
Took out over a dozen buildings in and around Gotham.
他就是上个月炸了军需供应所的那人
He's the one that blew up the commissary last month?
是的  他用火柴盒
Yeah, and he did it with match shavings
和苹果醋炸的
and apple cider vinegar.
所以今天不能有一丝差错  明白吗
So no mistakes today, got it?
把手举起来
Put your hands up.
她说这就是杀害你父母的凶手
She said this is the man who killed your parents.
她说她看见了他的脸
She said she saw his face.
你能认出他吗  布鲁斯
Do you recognize him, Bruce?
不能
No.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
塞琳娜・凯尔
Selina Kyle.
你相信她吗
Do you believe her?
相信
Yes, I do.
她看到了...
So, she saw...
全过程吗
everything?
你想让她跟我们住在这里吗
And you want her to live here with us, do you?
一个街头小偷
A common street criminal.
她比布鲁斯大不了多少
She's hardly older than Bruce.
她只是个看到了不该看的事的孩子
She's just a kid who's seen too much.
这是为了她的安全
This is for her safety.
哥谭市警局内鬼太多
GCPD is full of moles...
好吧  那你要让她跟我们待多久
Right, and how long would you have us put her up, then?
我不知道
I don't know.
不行  我不同意
No. The answer is no.
她在这里会给布鲁斯少爷带来危险
Her being here will put Master Bruce in great danger.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
她是凶杀案的证人  布鲁斯少爷
She is the witness to a murder, Master Bruce.
你明白这个中利害吧
You do understand that, don't you?
她也是我们找出杀害我父母凶手的最好的机会
She's also the best chance we have of finding who killed my parents.
不是吗
Isn't she?
是的
Yes, she is.
那么她可以留下
Then she can stay.
待多久都行
As long as it takes.
我已经决定了
I've made my decision.
是  布鲁斯少爷
Yes, Master Bruce.
听着  我知道这个要求有点过分
Look, I know this is a lot.
但我也是在尽我所能
But I'm doing everything I can.
蒙托亚  艾伦和我今天下午
Montoya and Allen and I are meeting
要和一位他们信任的助理地检官见面
with an ADA they trust this afternoon.
一个值得信赖的律师
A trustworthy lawyer.
还是在哥谭
In Gotham.
假如我们找到了凶手  我们就会需要她
Look, if we find this guy, we'll need her.
她得去作证
She'll have to testify.
在法官面前作证
Go before a judge.
那不会是件容易的事
It won't be easy.
证人常会临阵脱逃
Witnesses back out all the time.
而那些坚持到底的证人
The ones that stick it out do so
都是出于对受害者的关心
because they care about the victims.
那我们就要尽量好好待她了  不是吗
We'll do our best to be nice to her, then, won't we?
这是中国明朝的
It's from the Chinese Ming dynasty.
五...
Five...
五百年了
500 years old.
在唐人街花五块就能买到个一模一样的
You can get one just like it for five bucks, in Chinatown.
我叫布鲁斯・韦恩
I'm Bruce Wayne.
塞琳娜・凯尔
Selina Kyle.
大家叫我小猫
People call me Cat.
很高兴见到你  小猫
Nice to meet you, Cat.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
没干什么
Nothing.
你手里有什么
What's in your hand?
我说了  你手里...
I said, what's in...
怎么回事...
What the hell...?
翻译：灰灰是菇凉   Reginamoon   DustD   Silence
翻译：木浅薰   charcie   哥谭直属   夜影章鱼X   草草
时间轴：Kallen   凭陵新月   宝宝         后期：宝宝
特效：宝宝         校对&总监：草草
哈格罗夫
Hargrove!
伊恩・哈格罗夫  该走了
Ian Hargrove, time to go.
哥谭
第一季  第九集
小子  你搞砸了  很严重
Kid, you screwed up, big-time.
但你还年轻  理应再得到一次机会
But you're still young, you deserve a second chance.
所以我可以让你打个赌
So I have a bet for you.
你猜是头像还是数字
You call heads or tails.
猜错了  你就进监狱
You lose, you go to jail.
猜对了  我们就放你走
You win, we let you go.
-赌吧  -别急
- Bet. - Hold on.
有一个条件
There's a catch.
你得马上向上帝做出保证
You have to make a promise to God right now.
假如你猜中了  你就要把这当作他给你的启示
If you win, you're gonna take this as a sign from him
告诉你  你得回到学校
telling you that you need to go back to school
好好生活
and get your life straight.
你能保证吗
Can you promise that?
你会保证吗
Do you promise that?
会的  先生
Yes, sir.
那好吧
Okay then.
-猜吧  -头像
- Call. - Heads.
走吧  小子
Walk away, kid.
上面有人挺心疼你
Somebody up there loves you.
哈维
Hey, Harvey.
走吧
Go.
记住你的承诺
Remember your promise.
吉姆・戈登  哥谭市警局
Jim Gordon, GCPD.
我听过你不少好话  律师
I hear good things about you, counselor.
哈维・丹特  彼此彼此  警探
Harvey Dent, likewise about you, detective.
硬币那招挺有意思
That was some trick with the coin.
假如那孩子猜错了怎么办
What if the kid guesses wrong?
你会把他送进监狱吗
You gonna send him to jail?
青少年几乎都会猜头像
Teenagers, they nearly always call heads.
我也不知道为什么
I don't know why.
两面都是头像
Two-headed coin.
管用就好  是吧
Whatever works, right?
到底是谁  吉姆
So who is he, Jim?
是谁杀了韦恩夫妇
Who really killed the Waynes?
我们现在只有这张画
This is what we have.
不知道身份
No I.D.
但这是根据一位目击证人的描述画的吗
But this is from an eyewitness?
而且你已经安置好这人了
That you have in safe custody.
这点证据远远不够诉诸法律
It's not nearly enough to go to the law with.
即使我们掌握了这人的身份
Even if we had I.D. on this guy,
我们真正想找的是雇他杀人的人
it's the people who hired him we really want.
我同意
I agree.
你的目击证人在法庭上是没有用的
Your eyewitness is useless in a courtroom.
但你有个证人的说法
But the idea of your witness
是可以非常有价值的
could be immensely valuable.
听过迪克・洛夫克拉夫特吗
Ever hear the name Dick Lovecraft?
当然听过  亿万富翁
Sure. Billionaire.
地产  建筑  化工都有涉足
Property, construction, chemicals.
而且腐败透顶
And as corrupt as they come.
法尔科内  马罗尼  甚至韦恩集团
Falcone, Maroni, even Wayne Enterprises,
洛夫克拉夫特与他们都有交易
Lovecraft has dealings with all of them.
自韦恩夫妇死后  他财产倍增
Since the Waynes' deaths, he's doubled his fortune.
从阿卡姆项目也分得一大杯羹
Including a huge piece of the Arkham deal.
洛夫克拉夫特与托马斯・韦恩在
Lovecraft had a long feud with Thomas Wayne
生意与政见上长期不合
over deals and politics.
他们对高谭的未来看法完全不一样
They couldn't have had a more different vision for Gotham.
我愿以我的事业打赌
I'm willing to bet my career...
他有参与韦恩夫妇谋杀
on his involvement in the Wayne murders.
这赌还挺大
That's a big bet.
我想利用你的目击证人扳倒洛夫克拉夫特
I want to use your witness to go after Lovecraft.
怎么扳  我的证人无法证明
How? My witness can't connect
洛夫克拉夫特与罪犯有关
Lovecraft to the perp.
洛夫克拉夫特又不知道
Lovecraft doesn't know that.
我会让信息流出
I'll let it leak out
说我们有秘密目击证人
that we have a secret eyewitness
可以让案子豁然开朗
who's going to blow the case wide open
并证明洛夫克拉夫特与韦恩案有关
and connect Lovecraft to the Wayne killings.
洛夫克拉夫特会紧张
Lovecraft will get very nervous.
他身边的人也会紧张
And the people around him will get nervous.
然后就会有人松口  这种事你懂的
And that's when people start talking; you know how that goes.
除非洛夫克拉夫特没有参与韦恩谋杀
Unless Lovecraft wasn't involved in the Wayne murders.
即便如此  而我深表怀疑  我们也赢了
If so, which I doubt, we still win.
不管是谁参与了韦恩谋杀案
Whoever was involved in the Wayne killings
绝对会惊慌失措  对吧
will get their cage rattled like the dickens, won't they?
我打赌他会有所行动
I bet he makes a move.
你真喜欢打赌
You like to bet a lot.
对我们没有坏处
Well, what do we got to lose?
我的证人可能会成为目标
My witness becomes a target.
不会
No.
这就是美妙之处
That's the beauty of it.
我们不出书面文件
We never actually file papers.
完全不提名字
We never name names.
就只是一个有力的故事
It's just a powerful story.
你的证人绝对安全
Your witness is perfectly safe.
你们也认同这计划吗
And you're on board with this?
我们早认同了  吉姆
We've been on board, Jim.
哈维是咱们这边的
Harvey's one of us.
我与你的目标一致  吉姆
I want what you want, Jim.
我想让这个城市变得更好
I want to make this city a better place.
不提名字
No names.
不提我  不提我的证人  都不提
Not mine, not my witness, nothing--
只有一个故事
just a story.
Just a story.
好吧
All right.
我们试试
Let's try something.
我以为要自己去办这个案子了呢
Hey, I thought I was gonna have to work this case without you.
你去哪了
Where the hell have you been?
等等
You know what?
我改主意了  别说  我不想知道
On second thought, never mind, I don't want to know.
什么案子
What do we got?
一个大案
A biggie.
黑门监狱囚犯在转移去圣马可
Blackgate prisoner escaped while in transit
进行精神病治疗时逃走
to St. Mark's for psychiatric care.
他名叫伊恩・哈格罗夫  确诊精神病
His name's Ian Hargrove, clinically insane,
对炸东西有着强烈渴望
with a compulsion for blowing things up.
他炸掉了哥谭不少老建筑
He exploded a bunch of old buildings around Gotham.
最后一次  炸死了两个守卫
Last one, two janitors were killed.
这里说他被四名枪手劫出
Says here he was busted out by four gunmen?
是啊  很奇怪  哈格罗夫从没有同伙
Yeah, which is odd-- Hargrove never used accomplices.
好吧  哈格罗夫在黑门监狱里和谁有接触
All right, so who did Hargrove spend time with at Blackgate?
他和外面什么人有联系
Who did he communicate with on the outside?
他服刑期间一直与其他犯人隔离开
His entire stretch, he was isolated from gen pop.
从没打过或接过电话
Never made or received phone calls.
两年来只有一位探访者
Only one visitor in those two years--
他哥哥  约翰
his brother John.
-有地址吗  -有的
- Got an address? - We do.
警员正带他来接受询问
Unis are bringing him in right now for questioning.
幸好你还想着过来
We're lucky you deigned to show up.
抱歉
Yeah, sorry.
没事
No problem.
女人问题
Girl trouble?
嗯
Yeah.
早跟你说过
I told you.
上流社会的女人  会让你晕头转向
Those high society dames-- get you all twisted.
保持警惕
Keep your guard up.
动作快点
Knock lumps out of ya.
小心脚下
Watch your feet.
好了  刺拳  刺拳  右拳
Right... jab, jab, right.
先出拳
Lead with the...
刺拳  刺拳  右拳
Jab, jab, right. Jab, jab, right.
Jab, jab, right.
保持警惕  刺拳  刺拳  右拳
Keep that guard up-- jab, jab, right.
出拳  刺拳  刺拳  右拳
Lead... jab, jab, right.
刺拳  刺拳  右拳
Jab, jab, right.
保持...
Now keep that...
就这样
Yes.
对不起  阿尔弗雷德
Sorry, Alfred.
-你好  -布鲁斯
- Hello. - Bruce.
这样很疼
That hurt.
不疼才怪呢
Yeah, it's supposed to, isn't it?
承受打击
Taking a punch is
和出拳一样重要  布鲁斯少爷
just as important as throwing one, Master Bruce.
你在做什么
What you doing?
阿尔弗雷德在教我如何打拳
Alfred's teaching me to fight.
为什么
Why?
如果有坏事发生  我就会有所准备
So I'll be prepared if something bad happens.
是啊  因为你住的社区治安很差
Yeah, 'cause you live in a pretty rough neighborhood.
不是这里  是在哥谭
Not here, in Gotham.
在哥谭  没人戴手套打架
In Gotham, people don't fight with gloves on.
你的房间怎么样
How's your room?
还不错吧
Everything good?
还行
It'll do.
但是我饿了
I'm hungry, though.
早餐是上午8点  小姐
Right. Well, breakfast was served at 8:00, Miss,
你睡过头了
which you slept through.
午餐是中午12点
Lunch shall be served at 12:00.
厨房里有很多吃的
There's plenty to eat in the kitchen.
阿尔弗雷德会很乐意为你做一些
And Alfred will be happy to fix you something.
不  他不会
No, he won't be, will he?
因为这里不是酒店
Because it's not a bloody hotel.
算了  老头子
Relax, old man.
我自己会搞定的
I'll figure it out.
好  你可以顺便注意一下礼貌
Yeah, you can mind your manners as well,
你个厚脸皮的小丫头
you cheeky little minx.
对她好点  阿尔弗雷德  她是我们的客人
Be nice to her, Alfred, she's our guest.
万分抱歉  布鲁斯少爷
Well, I'm terribly sorry, Master Bruce.
没想到你喜欢她
Didn't realize you fancied her.
什么意思  我没喜欢她
What do you mean? N-No.
不必感到害羞
Well, it's nothing to be embarrassed about.
这很自然嘛
It's only natural, isn't it?
但是你防着她点
But you watch her.
她很傲慢
She's a lairy one.
好了  左拳  左拳  右拳
Right... left, left, right.
保持警惕  孩子
Keep your guard up, son.
你很了解女孩子吧  阿尔弗雷德
You know about girls, do you, Alfred?
看得比你清楚
Fair sight more than you.
而她  伙计
And she, mate,
是个麻烦精  小心
is trouble-- watch.
莉莎  莉莎
Liza, Liza...
你打的什么主意
what are you up to?
紫丁香
Lilacs.
我告诉你  我对他逃走的事一无所知
I'm telling you, I don't know anything about his escape.
我还没和他谈过
I haven't talked to him.
你的亲弟弟逃狱了  却没给你打电话
Your own baby brother busts out of prison, and doesn't call you,
这两年来他只和你一个人说过话
the only person he's talked to in two years?
发生了什么事
What happened?
你们俩闹翻了吗
You two have a falling out?
没  伊恩和我关系非常好
No, Ian and I are close.
一直都是
Always have been.
即使在他炸死了那些守卫之后吗
Even after he bombed those janitors?
那是场意外
That was an accident.
他们都这么说
That's what they all say.
这是事实
It's the truth.
我弟弟不是杀手
My brother's not a killer.
从来都不是
He never was.
他炸了哥谭12栋大楼
He blew up 12 buildings in Gotham.
没错  军工厂和他们的办公室
Yes, munitions factories and their offices.
制造枪支  弹药和导弹的地方
Places that made guns and bullets and missiles.
我知道他做错了
I know he was wrong,
但伊恩以为他是在做好事
but Ian thought that what he was doing was good.
最后一次爆炸案前他从未伤过人
He didn't hurt a soul until the last bombing.
而且他对伤到人万分难过
And he felt terrible about it.
他基本上是自己向警察投案的  还认了罪
He practically handed himself in to the cops and pleaded guilty.
伊恩从小就有精神问题
Ian has had mental problems ever since he was a kid.
我父母没钱给他治疗
My parents didn't have the money to get him the help he needed.
更别指望在黑门监狱得到治疗了
And he sure as hell wasn't getting it at Blackgate.
GGC冶金
听着
Look...
我弟弟不是坏人
my brother's not a bad man.
那他是什么样的人
Then what is he?
他是个病人
He's sick.
这是有区别的
There's a difference.
好吧
Okay...
那有谁会想劫囚
so who would want to bust him out?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我弟弟需要帮助
But my brother needs help.
你们一定要找到他
You have to find him.
做好了
It's done.
哥谭军工厂
有你的快递
I have a delivery for you.
给我吧
I'll take that.
谁送来的啊
Who sent this, anyway?
管他呢
Who cares?
等等
Wait a second.
你们听到了吗
You hear that?
像是走表的声音
Sounds like ticking.
爆炸震动哥谭
早上好
Good morning.
-睡得好吗  -你家房子一个劲儿响
- How'd you sleep? - Your house makes noise.
是老房子了
It's old.
你来的时候都没带什么东西
You didn't come here with much.
愿意的话  阿尔弗雷德可以为你买点衣服
If you want, Alfred can buy you some clothes.
不用
Pass.
戈登警探告诉我你在街头流浪
Detective Gordon told me you live on the streets.
没错
Yeah.
怎么了
So?
那是什么样儿
What's it like?
没这里好
Not as nice as here.
你一个人住吗
Do you live alone?
你打算盘问我一早上吗
Are you going to ask me questions all morning?
你不是应该去学校什么的吗
Aren't you supposed to be in school or something?
我有自己的课程计划
I'm developing my own curriculum.
这样我就可以按自己的速度
It lets me move at my own speed
专攻我感兴趣的学术领域
and focus on academic areas that interest me.
为什么
Why?
你已经是亿万富翁了  还有什么好学的
You're a billionaire, what's to learn?
这观点好奇怪
That's a strange attitude.
你爸妈呢
So, where are your parents?
他们还活着吗
They alive?
是啊
Sure.
他们还在
They're around.
在哪里
Where?
跟你有什么关系
What's that to you?
没什么  我只是想...
Nothing, I just thought...
是吗  那你想错了
Yeah, well, you thought wrong.
我不是孤儿
I'm not an orphan.
我有的是家人
I got family all over.
光是逃狱就已经够糟了
This was bad enough when it was just a prison escape.
现在又死了五个保安
Now we've got five dead security guards,
媒体已经称哈格罗夫为都市恐怖分子了
and the press is calling Hargrove an urban terrorist.
爆炸现场找到什么线索了吗
Did you get anything from the bombing site?
鉴证科还在调查
Forensics is still looking into it,
但整个办公室都毁了
but the entire office was destroyed.
-包括所有监控录像  -嗯
- Including all security footage. - Yeah.
不过我们能确定哈格罗夫和他的团伙偷走了
We do know that Hargrove and his guys made off
一种叫做环四亚甲基四硝胺的化合物
with a compound called HMX.
军方等级炸药
It's military grade.
威力是C4炸药的十倍
Ten times more powerful than C-4.
很恐怖的玩意儿
Nasty stuff.
用炸药来偷炸药
Using explosives to steal explosives.
这是要干什么
What's that about?
升级行动
Trading up?
他肯定还有其他目标
He must have another target in mind.
不易爆破的地方
Some place difficult to crack.
你们知道我要说什么吧
You know what I'm gonna say.
去吧  行动
So, go, do it.
我是戈登
This is Gordon.
你好  警探
Yes, detective.
是我  阿尔弗雷德
It's Alfred.
阿尔弗雷德  一切还好吗
Alfred, is everything all right?
塞琳娜还好吧
Is Selina okay?
她很安全
Well, she's safe.
但是呢
But?
但是警探  恐怕这样下去不行
But I'm afraid, detective, this isn't gonna work out.
她...挺麻烦的
She's a... a tough nut, this one.
要找到杀死韦恩夫妇的凶手
Well, look, we need her help if we have any chance
就需要她帮忙
of catching the Waynes' killer.
暂时看住她
Just hold onto her for now,
我会尽快抽空去看她的
and I'll be out to check on her as soon as I can.
那我们就耐心等你来了
We shall patiently await your arrival,
警探
detective.
一切都好吧
Everything good?
好得不得了
Right as rain.
你确定真要这样做
You sure you want to go through with this?
布奇  可不要现在退缩
Butch, don't you go getting scared on me now.
不会  老大
Never, boss.
奥斯瓦尔德  你回来了
Oswald, you're back.
我开始觉得你喜欢受伤
I'm starting to think you enjoy being hurt.
我只是路过
I was passing by.
就进来打个招呼
Thought I'd say hello.
招呼打完了
Well, you said it.
你怎么还不走
Now why are you here?
说实话  我只是想尽量对你友好些
Honestly, I'm just trying to be friendly.
紫丁香
Lilacs.
你真香
You smell good.
你真臭
You don't.
还是这么犀利
Snappy as ever.
再见了
Well, good-bye then.
抱歉你还这么生我气
Sorry you're still grumpy with me.
但是嘛
But, you know,
寻求友谊总错不了
reaching out in friendship is never wrong.
这家伙太}人了
Man, that dude's creepy.
别管他
Forget him.
他不值一提
He's nothing.
这些是哈格罗夫进黑门监狱之前的
Hargrove's contacts and phone records
所有联系人和通话记录
from before he went to Blackgate.
-你还好吧  -很好
- You all right? - Yeah, yeah.
芭芭拉离开了
Barbara left.
-彻底离开  -是的
- Left left? - Yeah.
去哪了
Where'd she go?
不知道
I don't know.
策略而已
It's a ploy.
是以退为进地逼婚
She wants you to set a date.
典型手法
It's a standard move.
她会回来的
She'll be back.
你们玩电子游戏吗
Do you play video games?
爱德  再不许这么干了
Ed, don't ever do that again.
抱歉  警探
My apologies, detective.
你们俩谁玩电子游戏吗
Do either of you play video games?
我玩
I do, I...
我超喜欢电子游戏
I love video games.
我觉得每个游戏都是新的挑战  一个谜
I find that each one presents a new challenge, a puzzle.
很像警探办案
It's a lot like detective work in that way.
爱德
Ed.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我分析了保安室找到的弹片
Uh, I had a chance to analyze the shrapnel from the security office.
结果找到了这个
And I found something.
是个铭牌
It's a nameplate.
因为爆炸有些受损
It was damaged in the bombing,
但还能认出上面的字迹
but you can still read the information.
GGC冶金
这是哥谭一间废弃冶金厂的
It's from an abandoned metal factory here in Gotham.
干得不错  爱德
That's really good work, Ed.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢你  警探
Thank you, Detective.
咱们去查查这个
Let's go check this out.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
不许动
Freeze!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
你们找到铭牌了  感谢上帝
You found the nameplate, thank God.
这里还有其他人吗
Is anyone else here?
没有  但他们很快就会回来
No, but they'll be back soon.
求你们帮帮我
Please, you got to help me.
他们劫了囚  绑架了我
They broke me out of prison, they kidnapped me,
他们说如果我不帮他们  他们就杀了我哥哥
they told me they'd kill my brother and his family
以及他家人
if I didn't help them.
-"他们"是谁  -俄国人
- Who's "they"? - Russians.
其中一个名叫卡西亚诺夫
One of their names is-is Kasyanov.
他们在计划对付法尔科内
They're planning something against Falcone.
-法尔科内  -对
- Falcone? - Yeah.
要干票大的  是个保险库
It's a, it's a big job, a vault.
所以他们需要我来做炸药
That's why they needed me to build explosives.
-什么情况  -找掩护
- What's this? - Take cover.
你们身后
Behind you!
趴下  趴下
Get down, get down!
把他抓过来
Get the guy.
离开这里
Get out of here!
-救命  -快走
- Help me! - Move. Move.
你要是想出去
If you want to go somewhere,
我们可以给你叫辆出租车
we can call you a taxi.
你动作很轻
You move quiet.
你也是
So do you.
你要走了吗
Are you leaving?
在考虑
Thinking about it.
如果提起你家人让你难过了  我很抱歉
I'm sorry if talking about your family upset you.
我没有难过
I wasn't upset.
你看起来有点难过
You seemed kind of upset.
那是你妈妈  对吧
That's your mom, huh?
她看起来不错
She looks nice.
是啊
She was.
她被杀那晚
You saw her...
你看见她了吗
the night she was killed?
你看见我了吗
And you saw me?
我做了什么
What I did?
没做什么
What I didn't do?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你能做什么
What could you have done?
我不知道  总能做点什么
I don't know-- something.
你在做梦吧  孩子
You're dreaming, kid.
那可是枪啊
A gun's a gun.
我妈妈是娱乐界的
My mom's in show business.
真的
Yeah.
她唱歌  跳舞  变魔术
She sings and dances and does magic tricks.
身价百万
Gets paid, like, millions.
但那只是伪装
But that's just a cover.
她实际上是政府的间谍
Really, she's a secret agent for the government.
没错
Yeah.
她在执行秘密任务
She's on a secret mission.
等她结束工作后  就会回来找我
But when she's done, she's coming back to get me.
那不错
That's good.
是啊
Yeah.
你亲过女孩子吗
Did you ever kiss a girl?
没有
No.
你想亲吗
Do you want to?
你问这个干什么
Why-why do you ask?
只是好奇
Just curious.
该学习了  布鲁斯少爷
Time for your studies, Master Bruce.
谢谢你  阿尔弗雷德
Thank you, Alfred.
欢迎你加入我们  凯尔小姐
You're more than welcome to join, Miss Kyle.
得了吧
Right.
回见
I'll see you later.
你知道我们这周接到了多少
Do you have any idea how many angry phone calls
愤怒的电话吗
we've been getting this week?
外头有个恐怖分子
Got a terrorist out there.
是我们的错吗
And that's our fault?
吉姆
Jim!
不  没事
No, no, please.
告诉我  警探
You tell me, Detective--
这怎么成了我的错呢
how is this my fault?
首先
Well, for starters,
你把精神病人关在黑门
you have the mentally ill housed at Blackgate,
那座监狱没有任何相关设施
a prison with no facilities for them.
你只好送他们出去就医
So, you send them out for treatment,
哈格罗夫正是在外出就医的路上
which was exactly where Hargrove was headed
被劫囚了
when he was broken out.
给我找到他
I want him found.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
今天就找到
Today.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
你什么毛病
What is wrong with you?
对了  哈格罗夫的哥哥约翰
By the way, Hargrove's brother John,
我对他和他的家人进行了保护性监禁
I went ahead and put him and his family in protective custody.
挺好
That'll help.
是啊  唯一的问题是
Yeah, only problem is--
哈格罗夫还不知道
Hargrove doesn't know that.
好了  丹特
All right, Dent.
你把我找来了  你想怎样
You dragged me down here, now what?
我找到了最后一块拼图
I got the last piece of the puzzle in place.
我要起诉你
I'm bringing charges against you.
又老调重弹啊
Oh, that old song again?
你永远别想证明欺诈
You will never prove fraud.
这你清楚  我也清楚
You know that, and I know that.
欺诈指控只是诸多罪名中的一项
Fraud charges are only part of it.
是吗  还有什么  乱穿马路吗
Oh, really? What, then? Jaywalking?
合谋犯下一级谋杀罪
Conspiracy to commit first-degree murder.
谋杀
Murder?
告诉我  丹特
So, tell me, Dent--
我杀谁了
who did I kill?
托马斯和玛莎・韦恩夫妇
Thomas and Martha Wayne.
我的天
Oh, God...
我有个目击证人能指证你与这起案子有关
I have an eyewitness who can tie you to the crime,
并指认其他的涉案人员
you and all the others involved.
一派胡言
That's absurd.
帮你自己个忙吧  迪克
Help yourself out here, Dick.
慎重考虑你的选择
Think about your options.
情势对你很不利啊
This is gonna get ugly.
你个傻子
You're a fool.
你根本不知道你在跟谁
And you have no idea who
跟什么势力打交道
or what you're even dealing with.
你再威胁我试试
Don't you ever threaten me!
我生撕了你
I will rip you open.
见到你很愉快  迪克
It was good to see you, Dick.
吉姆
Jim!
有发现
Got it.
是吗
Yeah?
这是格莱戈・卡西亚诺夫
Meet Gregor Kasyanov.
罪行累累
Long rap sheet.
尼古拉活着的时候是他手下
Worked for Nikolai before he died.
他现在给谁干活儿
Who does he work for now?
我不知道
Beats me.
那好
All right.
哈格罗夫说是一个大单  一个保险库
Hargrove said it's a big job, right? A vault.
肯定有人背后出钱
Somebody's got to be bankrolling it.
是啊  某个和法尔科内有嫌隙的有钱大佬
Yeah, someone with cash and pull and beef with Falcone.
问题是在哥谭
Problem is-- in Gotham,
随便哪个有钱大佬都和法尔科内有过节
anyone with cash and pull has beef with Falcone.
那能是谁呢
So, who is it?
你让我好等啊
You kept me waiting.
碰上了点麻烦
Ran into a little trouble.
没什么可担心的
Nothing to worry about.
那就好  我对这单活儿寄予厚望
Good, I've got a lot riding on this job.
你说过了
You've said.
你老板尼古拉死了
Your boss Nikolai is dead
都因为法尔科内
because of Falcone.
你要是想报复他
You want to get back at him,
就得戳他痛处  拿他的钱开刀
you hit him where it hurts-- his money.
对不对  布奇
Ain't that right, Butch?
对头
Yep.
万恶之源
The root of all evil.
我们会抢他的钱
We'll take his money.
这点没问题
No problem.
只要你提供的地点准确
As long as it's there, like you said.
绝对准确
Oh, it's there.
我非常肯定
I'm positive.
这是你要的卡车
The truck you needed.
还有  格莱戈
And Gregor...
祝你好运
break a leg.
你是我见过的最怪的孩子
You're the weirdest kid I've ever met.
你为什么那么做
Why are you doing that?
训练
Training.
就像拳击
Like the boxing.
那么  如果有人用跳水板抢劫你
So, if anyone mugs you with a diving board,
你就会有所准备了  是吗
you'll be ready, huh?
对
Yes.
不是
I mean, no.
我在培养自我控制和意志力
I'm developing self-discipline and willpower.
为什么
Why?
好变得强壮
So I can be strong.
我懂  但这是行不通的
I get you, but it won't work.
在外面  在哥谭是没用的
Not on the streets, not in Gotham.
为什么
Why's that?
在外面混
Out there on the streets,
光强壮是不够的
it's not enough to be strong.
你得坏
You gotta be mean.
你得无情
Gotta be ruthless.
你知道那是什么意思吗
Do you know what ruthless means?
当然
Of course I do.
是吗
Yeah?
你不是那样的
Well, you ain't.
你是个好孩子
You're a nice kid.
你在外面混5分钟  就会被人宰割
Five minutes on the street, you'll be mincemeat.
会闭气对你毫无帮助
And holding your breath won't do a damn thing.
今天的主题是  数字
The subject of today's category is numbers.
开始了
Here we go.
人体手臂有多少根骨头
How many bones in the human arm?
32根
Thirty-two.
正确
Correct.
接下来  元素周期表有多少种元素
Next, how many elements in the periodic table?
118种
118.
Uh... 118.
再次正确
Yes, again.
这个要难了
Now for a tough one.
一叠纸牌上有多少只眼睛
How many eyes are there on cards in a deck?
42个
Forty-two.
21个
21.
抱歉  错了
No, I'm sorry.
应该是42个
The number you were looking for is 42.
一双眼睛是两只眼睛哦
You forgot to double it for two eyes.
今天的节目到此结束
Well, that concludes our show for today.
感谢所有参赛者
We'd like to thank all the contestants
前来演播室参与节目
that participated here in studio
也感谢在家跟着一起参与的听众们
and those of you playing along at home.
我们稍后就回来
We'll be back right after this.
好了  慢慢说
Okay, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
爆炸物怎么了
What about the explosives?
种类很特别
It-it's a very specific type.
十分不稳定
It's highly volatile,
而且很难制造
and it's very difficult to manufacture.
只有一个用处
It's for one use, and one use only.
穿透铁
To penetrate iron.
比如银行的保险库
Like a vault in a bank.
不不  那都是钢板
Mm-mm, no, they're all steel.
现在没人拿铁做东西了
No one makes anything out of iron anymore.
至少有一世纪了
Not for... A hundred years, at least.
哥谭军械库
The Gotham Armory.
嗯
Yeah.
那里有铁保险库
Yeah, they have those iron vaults
里面有火药
they used to keep the gunpowder in.
几年前
A few years ago,
那里被一个私人投资集团买下了
a private investment group bought it.
肯定是法尔科内叫人做的
Ten to one, Falcone's behind it.
你们要...
Do you...?
哥谭军械库地下室
还要多久
How much longer?
好了
It's ready.
不好使
It didn't work.
向我保证不会再有人受伤了
Promise me nobody else is gonna get hurt.
嗯嗯  行啊  没问题
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sure, no problem.
我保证
Cross my heart.
你们被包围了
You're surrounded!
无路可退了
There's no way out!
放下武器
Drop your weapons!
别过来  退后
Don't do it! Get back!
哈格罗夫
Hargrove!
伊恩・哈格罗夫
Ian Hargrove!
你哥哥和他家人都安全
Your brother and his family are safe.
我们把他们保护监禁起来了
We have them in protective custody.
他如果跑  就打死他
If he runs, shoot him!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
你开枪打他  他们会打我们
You shoot him, they shoot us!
放下武器
Drop your weapons!
未知来电
快离开车
Get away from the truck!
趴下
Everybody down!
你干什么
Why'd you do that?
你肯定不会打我
Bet you can't hit me.
我能
I could.
但我为什么要打你
But why would I want to?
试试吧
Try.
为什么
What for?
打我
Hit me, and...
我就让你亲我
I'll let you kiss me.
没打着
You didn't get me.
糟糕
Ah, no!
早啊  阿尔弗雷德
Morning, Alfred.
警探
Ah, Detective.
我一直想过去
I've been trying to get out there.
真抱歉  一切都好吗
I'm sorry, uh... Is everything okay?
她乖吗
Is she behaving herself?
不怎么乖
Well, uh, not really, no.
不过没关系
That's all right.
是吗
It is?
嗯  她...
Yes, well, she's...
可以说是一股清新之风
a breath of fresh air, I might say.
那太好了
Glad to hear it.
我会尽快过去的
I'll be out there as-as soon as I can.
好的  先生
Very good, sir.
抱歉不请自来
Forgive me for the intrusion,
但我必须马上跟你谈话
but it's urgent that I speak with you.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am.
嗯
Yeah.
法尔科内如果知道你来这里会杀了你的
And Falcone would kill you if he knew you were here.
或许吧
Perhaps.
但如果我告诉他
What would he do if I told him
你在替菲什・穆尼监视他  他会怎么做
that you were spying on him for Fish Mooney?
你没有证据
You don't have any proof.
没有
No.
但怀疑  是件有趣的事
But suspicion, it's a funny thing.
法尔科内起初或许不会信我
Falcone might not choose to believe me at first,
但他每次看见你
but every time he looked at you,
都会自问  她是间谍吗
he'd ask himself-- is she?
可能吗
Could she?
会吗
Would she?
你错了
You're wrong.
他在乎我
He cares about me.
那我们就打给他  看看谁对谁错吧
Let's call him and find out, shall we?
住手
Stop!
我不会泄露你的秘密
Your secret is safe with me.
我不说出去
I won't tell,
因为你
because you...
要继续为菲什工作
are gonna keep working for Fish.
这事你谁都不能说
And you are not going to tell anyone.
否则你会没命
Or you'll die.
给戈登的留言
Messages for Gordon.
谢谢
Thanks.
吉姆  有时间吗
Jim. You have a minute?
有
Uh, yeah.
我见过洛夫克拉夫特了
I met with Lovecraft.
怎么样
How'd it go?
他怕了
He was scared.
他肯定与这事有关
He's involved, all right.
怕不是证据
Scared isn't proof.
你没见到他的样子
You didn't see him.
我在其他地方也散播了这个说法
Told the same story in a few other spots.
现在重要的人物都该听说了
All the big players will know by now,
肯定会有人松口的
someone will start talking.
到时候
If and when they do,
我们要先商量再行动
neither of us makes a move without talking first.
我们要一起进退
We move together on this.
当然
Absolutely.
哈格罗夫案干得好
Hey, nice work on the Hargrove case.
你救了他一命
You saved the poor guy's life.
你真是个圣人
You're a regular saint.
谢了  希望我们很快能再聊
Thanks. Uh, we'll be talking again soon, I hope.
当然
You bet.
谢了  律师
Thanks, Counselor.
哈格罗夫手续都办好了
Finish up with Hargrove?
嗯
Yeah.
他正在去往阿卡姆的路上
He's on his way to Arkham.
阿卡姆
Arkham?
市长命令
Mayor's directive.
他要把黑门监狱的所有精神病罪犯
He's taking all the criminally insane inmates from Blackgate,
转移去阿卡姆
sending them to Arkham,
好让他们得到妥善治疗
so they can get appropriate treatment.
简直是疯了
That's nuts.
妥善...那栋建筑都两百岁了
Appropriate tr... The building's 200 years old.
哥谭就这样
Welcome to Gotham.
对了  哈格罗夫说炸毁钱的炸弹
Oh, and get this-- Hargrove said that the bomb that blew up the money
不是他安放的
wasn't his.
那是谁
Whose was it?
他不知道
He didn't know.
怎么样
How did it go?
警察到处都是
Cops were everywhere.
我们的人无路可逃
Our guys had no way out.
我只能当机立断
I had to make the call.
他们都死了吗
Is everybody dead?
格莱戈  他的手下
Gregor? All his men?
都死了
Every last one.
很好
Good.
不能留下麻烦
I can't stand loose strings.
你不生气
You're not mad?
我们刚刚损失了不少钱啊
That's a hell of a lot of money we just lost.
生气
Mad?
我高兴极了
I couldn't be happier.
我们不是要偷钱  布奇
The point wasn't to steal that money, Butch.
是要伤到法尔科内
It was to hurt Falcone.
这你做到了  菲什
Well, that you did, Fish.
这你做到了
That you did.
大家下午好
Good afternoon, everyone.
谢谢前来
Thank you all for coming.
各位都知道
As you well know,
哥谭人民颇受最近发生的惨剧的震动
the people of Gotham have been shaken by tragedy in recent days,
市民不该经受如此惨剧
tragedy no citizen should have to endure.
阿卡姆精神病院
这几天来发生的事
What has happened these past few days
是哥谭精神病罪犯没有得到
is a direct result of Gotham's criminally insane
妥善治疗的直接结果
not getting the appropriate treatment and help
这是我们欠他们的
that we owe them.
所以我要执行将刚翻修过的
That is why I am moving forward with plans
阿卡姆精神病院
to turn the recently renovated Arkham Asylum
改造成治疗中心的计划
into a remedial facility...
行了  赶紧走吧
All right, let's go, here, man; let's go.
那里将专门关押精神病罪犯
...for the criminally insane.
芭芭拉
Barbara...
是我
it's me.
我收到你的信了
I got your letter, and I, um...
我知道你说你需要离开哥谭一阵
I know you said you needed some time away from Gotham.
离开我
From me.
但我希望你回来
But I want you to come back.
我需要你回来
I need you... to come back.
没了你我什么都没了
I don't have anything without you.
我爱你
And I love you.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com